Earl Browder Papers
Earl Browder Papers
1879-1990
Browder, Earl, 1891-1973.
48.0 linear ft.
Papers of the General secretary of the Communist Party of the United States from 1930 through its dissolution in 1944. When the Party was reconstituted as the Communist Political Association later that year, Browder was chosen as its President, however he was expelled in 1946 following a debate over Party leadership. Following his expulsion, Browder lectured and wrote about Marxism and represented Soviet writers and publishers for publication in the United States. Collection includes correspondence/subject files (1879-1970) relating to Marxist philosophy, the workings of the C.P.U.S.A., Browder's role within the Party and to Browder's business ventures as well as legal files (1938-1958); manuscripts (1924-1967) of Browder and others, including Browder's manuscripts for articles, books, memoranda, news releases, pamphlets, reports, and speeches; and memorabilia including personal files and photographs of Browder and his family, and some colleagues. Notable correspondents include Roger Baldwin, Daniel Bell, Bruce Bliven, Rudy Blum, Louis B. Boudin, Juan Antonio Corretjer, Theodore Draper, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, William Z. Foster, Joseph Freeman, A.A. Heller, Lotte Jacobi, Alfred Kohlberg, Robert S. Minor, Tom Mooney, Paul and Eslanda Goode Robeson, Anna Rochester, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jack Selford, Joseph R. Starobin, I.F. Stone, John Strachey, Anna Louise Strong, Dirk Jan Struik, Norman Thomas, Harry Frederick Ward, Sumner Welles, and others. Also included is a holograph letter of greeting from Mao Zedong. The collection also includes Browder's personal library and other published materials.
148870
Biographical History
Earl Russell Browder (1891-1973) was General Secretary of the Communist party of the United States during the height of its popularity, in the 1930s and 1940s and twice represented the Party as its candidate for President. Earl Browder was born on May 20, 1891, in Wichita, Kansas. He was the son of William Browder and Martha Jane Hankins Browder. His father was a teacher and farmer who was avidly Populist. Earl Browder had little formal education and went to work to help support the family. At the age of 15 Browder joined the Socialist party, but within a few years he moved on to the newly formed Syndicalist League of North America, led by William Z. Foster. He took courses in law and business and became manager of a cooperative store in Olathe, Kansas where he authored a manual on the principles of accounting for cooperatives. In 1917, Browder was convicted of espionage for speaking out against potential US involvement in World War I and following his release from prison continued to oppose the war and was again convicted and served a second sentence. Soon after he left prison in 1919, he joined the newly organized Communist party. He also went to work for Foster's Trade Union Educational League (TUEL) in New York City. In 1921 Browder and Foster represented the TUEL at the Red International of Labor Unions (RILU) in Moscow. Browder became a top aide to Foster. In 1926 Browder travelled to Moscow and then China as part of an international Communist labor delegation. Returning to the United States in 1929, Browder helped Foster become General Secretary of the party. When poor health forced Foster into semi-retirement in 1932, Browder succeeded to the party leadership. During the 15 years of his leadership, the Communist party grew from a membership of a few thousand to over 100,000 and gained both visibility and considerable respectability with Browder as its "face" and "voice". Browder was the Party's candidate for President in 1936 and 1940, both times with James W. Ford as his running mate. In 1940, Browder was convicted of passport fraud and sentenced to four years in federal prison in Atlanta but his sentence was commuted by President Roosevelt after 14 months. In the election of 1944, Browder supported Roosevelt's reelection and presided over the dissolution of the United States Communist Party and the formation of the Communist Political Association. In 1946, Browder and his brother William were both expelled from the international Communist Party. Following his expulsion, Earl Browder wrote and lectured and worked with Soviet publishers and authors to get their books published in the United States. Browder died in Princeton, NJ on June 27, 1973.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Earl Browder Papers consists of biographical material, correspondence-subject files, writings and memorabilia.
Biographical material comprises biographical sketches, obituaries and genealogical material.
Correspondence-subject files comprise approximately half the collection. Represented here are important individuals in the Communist and Socialist movements such as (Benjamin Davis, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, James W. Ford, William Z. Foster, Vito Marcantonio, Upton Sinclair, Norman Thomas and Mao Zedong). There are extensive transcipts of early Central Committee Plenum sessions (March, April 1930) and other early organizing meetings of the Communist Party USA and the TUEL. Correspondence with and reports about labor unions, other political parties ( American Labor Party, Henry Wallace's Progressive Party, Socialist Party), and organizations (International Labor Defense, National Council for Prevention of War ) are also well represented. Boxes 10 through 15 contain material directly relating to the Communist Party USA or to Communist parties in various countries including Canada, Cuba, Greece, Mexico, Peru, Poland, Spain and New Zealand. Also represented are a number of publications ( The Daily Worker, New Masses), publishers (Duke University Press, Haldeman-Julius Publications, Oxford University Press, OGIZ), and booksellers ( [Irving] Ephraim, O'Brien Antiquarian Bookseller), as well as educational institutions (Cornell University, New York University, Princeton University). Extensive legal files concerning Earl Browder's passport violation case (United States v. Earl Browder 22 USC 220) and Raissa Browder's deportation case (United States v. Raissa Berkmann Browder) are included. There is also family correspondence including letters to and from Earl Browder and his wife Raisa during Browder's time in jail. Correspondence of Browder's sons Felix, Andrew and William which is related to their own careers has been included in Memorabilia.
Writings contains articles (including letters to the editor), books and speeches, almost all on political topics relating to labor problems and/or Communism. Sample titles/topics include "The Communist Party and Civil Liberties in the United States," "How To Tell an Anti-Democrat and How To Beat Him," and "Cooperation with Communists." Of particular interest in this series are several versions of Browder's autobiography, which was never completed or published. There is a great deal of duplication of text among articles, speeches and pamphlets as Browder's speeches were often published in multiple forms.
Memorabilia includes address books, artwork, clippings about Browder from a wide range of publications, financial material, and photographs of Browder, both personal (family and friends) and political (Communist International 7th World Congress). Also included in Memorabilia are postcards which Browder brought back or sent to his sons for their postcard albums, printed material, a number of sound recordings, and travel souvenirs.
Other Formats Available
All audiorecordings have been digitized.
Arrangement of the Collection
Biographical material, Correspondence-subject files and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by topic or subject. Writings are subdivided by type; within that, articles and speeches are arranged chronologically while books are alphabetical by title.
Separated Material
A number of published items were sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to and search on "Gift of Earl Browder" to locate these items. In addition, Rare Books has substantial cataloged holdings of Communist publications such as the New Masses, Communist International and Bolʹshevik. Please refer to for these items as well.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Radicalism; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Adams, Josephine Truslow.; Agapov, B. N. (Boris Nikolaevich); Albizu Campos, Pedro, 1891-1965.; Alter, Victor, 1890-1941.; Alvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1891-; Amter, I. (Israel), 1881-; Anderson, Clinton Presba, 1895-1975.; Angell, Norman, 1874-1967.; Arze, José Antonio, 1904-1955.; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981.; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965.; Bassols, Narciso.; Bedacht, Max, 1883-1972.; Beneŝ, Edvard, 1884-1948.; Beria, L. P. (Lavrentĭ Pavlovich), 1899-1953.; Berti, Giuseppe, 1901-; Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985.; Bethune, Norman.; Biddle, Francis, 1886-1968.; Billings, Warren K., 1893-1972.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977.; Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951.; Blossom, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1878-; Boudin, Louis B. (Louis Boudianoff), 1874-1952.; Bransten, Richard, 1906-1955.; Bridges, Harry, 1901-1990.; Browder, Andrew.; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973.; Browder, Felix E.; Browder, Raissa.; Browder, William.; Brown, William Montgomery, 1855-1937.; Budenz, Louis F. (Louis Francis), 1891-1972.; Cacchione, Peter V., 1897-1947.; Celler, Emanuel, 1888-1981.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; Chambers, Whittaker.; Chen, Jiageng, 1874-1961.; Ćopić, Vladimir, 1891-1939.; Corretjer, Juan Antonio.; Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.; Cousins, Norman.; Curran, Edward Lodge, b. 1898.; Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1881-1950.; Darcy, Samuel, 1905-; Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), 1903-1964.; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926.; Dedijer, Stevan.; Dennis, Eugene, 1905-1961.; Dirksen, Everett McKinley.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976.; Dowling, Lyle.; Draper, Theodore, 1912-2006.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Drinan, Robert F.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Duclos, Jacques, 1896-1975.; Dutt, R. Palme (Rajani Palme), 1896-1974.; Dvorine, Israel, 1900-1989.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1897-1977.; Efries, Joseph.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Ehrlich, Henryk, 1882-1942.; Field, Frederick V. (Frederick Vanderbilt), 1905-2000.; Field, Marshall, 1893-1956.; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley.; Ford, James W., 1893-1957.; Foster, William Z., 1881-1961.; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967.; Freeman, Joseph, 1897-1965.; Gallagher, Leo.; Ganley, Nat, 1903-1969.; Gantt, W. Horsley (William Horsley), 1892-1980.; Garlin, Sender.; Gauvreau, Emile, 1891-1956.; Gold, Mike.; Goldman, Marcus I. (Marcus Isaac), 1881-; Green, Gil, 1906-; Gropper, William, 1897-1977.; Hall, Gus.; Heller, A. A. (Abraham Aaron), 1874-; Herndon, Angelo, 1913-1997.; Hoffa, James R. (James Riddle), 1913-; Houphouët-Boigny, Félix, 1905-1993.; Hsieh, Tehyi, b. 1884.; Hunt, R. N. Carew (Robert Nigel Carew); Hutchins, Grace, 1885-1969.; Ibárruri, Dolores, 1895-1989.; Jacobi, Lotte, 1896-1990.; Jaffe, Philip J. (Philip Jacob), 1895-1980.; Jiménez Malaret, René.; Jordan, Virgil, 1892-1965.; Kalinin, M. I. (Mikhail Ivanovich), 1875-1946.; Keating, Kenneth B. (Kenneth Barnard), 1900-1975.; Kennan, George F. (George Frost), 1904-2005.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971.; Kohlberg, Alfred, 1887-1960.; Kōtoku, Shūsui, 1871-1911.; Lachatañeré, R. (Rómulo); Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Lampe, Alfred, 1900-1943.; Lange, Oskar, 1904-1965.; Lannon, Albert Vetere, 1938-; Lash, Joseph P., 1909-1987.; Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950.; Law, Richard, 1901-1980.; Lazarsfeld, Paul F., 1901-1976.; Lefkowitz, Louis J.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Levine, Isaac Don, 1892-1981.; Le Sueur, Meridel.; Li, Lisan, 1899-1967.; Libby, Frederick J. (Frederick Joseph), 1874-1970.; Lieber, Maxim, 1897-1993.; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974.; Lipset, Seymour Martin.; Little, Herbert S. (Herbert Satterthwaite), 1902-1972.; Lloyd, William Bross, 1908-; Lombardo Toledano, Vicente, 1894-1968.; Lovestone, Jay.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.; Lumpkin, Katharine Du Pre, 1897-1988.; Lunacharsky, Anatoly Vasilievich, 1875-1933.; Lyons, Eugene, 1898-1985.; MacDermot, Niall.; Magil, A. B. (Abraham Bernard), 1905-; Mann, Tom, 1856-1941.; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976.; Marcantonio, Vito, 1902-1954.; Marinello, Juan, 1898-1977.; Marty, André.; Maverick, Maury, 1895-1954.; McClure, Wallace, 1890-; McCormick, Anne O'Hare, 1880-1954.; McNaboe, John J., 1893-1954.; McWilliams, Carey, 1905-1980.; Merriman, Robert Hale.; Minor, Robert S.; Mitchell, Broadus, 1892-1988.; Mooney, Tom.; Morris, R. J. (Robert John); Mostel, Zero, 1915-1977.; Mowrer, Edgar Ansel, 1892-1977.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Nance, Ellwood C. (Ellwood Cecil), 1900-; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Ney, Lew.; Nobile, Umberto, 1885-1978.; North, Joseph.; O'Sheel, Shaemas, 1886-1954.; Pass, Joseph.; Pegler, J. Westbrook (James Westbrook), 1894-1969.; Pesenti, Antonio.; Pollitt, Harry.; Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1908-1972.; Preveden, Francis Ralph, 1890-1959.; Quill, Mike, 1905-1966.; Rabello, Manoel.; Rajk, László, 1909-1949.; Rautenstrauch, Walter, 1880-1951.; Reid, Helen Rogers, 1882-1970.; Revyuk, Emil.; Rico, Dan, 1912-1985.; Riesel, Victor.; Robb, Roger.; Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1896-1965.; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976.; Rochester, Anna.; Rogge, O. John (Oetje John), 1903-1981.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Rossiter, Clinton, 1917-1970.; Roumain, Jacques, 1907-1944.; Rudensky, Red, 1898-; Russell, Richard B. (Richard Brevard), 1897-1971.; Rutledge, Wiley, Jr., 1894-1949.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979.; Sayre, John Nevin, 1884-1977.; Schafer, John Charles, 1893-1962.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Schuyler, George S. (George Samuel), 1895-1977.; Seipp, Conrad, 1920-; Shub, Anatole.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Slochower, Harry, 1900-1991.; Smith, Gerald L. K. (Gerald Lyman Kenneth), 1898-1976.; Smith, Vern Ralph, 1892-; Snow, Sinclair.; Sokolsky, George E. (George Ephraim), 1893-1962.; Song, Qingling, 1893-1981.; Spivak, Lawrence E. (Lawrence Edmund), 1900-1994.; Stachel, Jack.; Stalin, Joseph, 1878-1953.; Starobin, Joseph R. (Joseph Robert), 1913-1976.; Stern, Carl S. (Carl Samuel); Stettinius, Edward R., Jr. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Stone, I. F. (Isidor Feinstein), 1907-1989.; Strachey, John, 1901-1963.; Strong, Anna Louise, 1885-1970.; Struik, Dirk J. (Dirk Jan), 1894-2000.; Tarasov-Rodionov, A. (Aleksandr), 1885-; Telford, Shirley, 1925-; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Thye, Edward John, 1896-1969.; Tito, Josip Broz, 1892-1980.; Toohey, Patrick, 1911-1982.; Trachtenberg, Alexander, 1884-1966.; Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943.; Trimble, South.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965.; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961.; Wicks, Harry, 1905-1989.; Wilder, Isabel, 1900-1995.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Wilson, Earl, 1907-1987.; Winchell, Walter, 1897-1972.; Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1894-1972.; Wolfe, Bertram David, 1896-1977.; Yarborough, Ralph Webster, 1903-1996.; Young, Art, 1866-1943.; Zhdanov, Andrei Andreevich.; Zhou, Enlai, 1898-1976.; American Civil Liberties Union.; American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.; American Federation of Labor.; American Federation of Teachers.; American Labor Party.; American Labor Party. -- Progressive Committee.; American League Against War and Fascism.; American Legion.; American Negro Labor Congress.; Associated Press.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Columbia University.; Communist International.; Communist Party (Algeria); Communist Party (Argentina); Communist Party of Australia.; Communist Party (Austria); Communist Party (Bolivia); Communist Party (Brazil); Communist Party of Canada.; Communist Party (Chile); Communist Party (China); Communist Party (Colombia); Communist Party (Costa Rica); Communist Party (Cuba); Communist Party (Czechoslovakia); Communist Party (France); Communist Party (Germany); Communist Party (Great Britain); Communist Party (Greece); Communist Party (Haiti); Communist Party (Honduras); Communist Party (Hungary); Communist Party (India); Communist Party (Ireland); Communist Party (Italy); Communist Party (Mexico); Communist Party (Morocco); Communist Party (New Zealand); Communist Party (Peru); Communist Party of the Philippines (1930- ); Communist Party (Poland); Communist Party (Puerto Rico); Communist Party (Spain); Communist Party (South Africa); Communist Paty (Soviet Union); Communist Party of the United States of America.; Communist Party U.S.A. (Opposition); Communist Party (Uruguay); Communist Party (Venezuela); Communist Party (Yugoslavia); Communist Political Association.; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Farmer-Labor Party (Minn.); Fund for the Republic.; Haldeman-Julius Company.; Imperial War Museum (Great Britain); Industrial Workers of the World.; International Fellowship of Reconciliation.; International Labor Defense.; League of American Writers.; League for Industrial Democracy.; Liberal Party of New York State.; Library of Congress.; McGraw-Hill Book Company; National Council for Prevention of War (U.S.); National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (U.S.); National Federation for Constitutional Liberties.; National Lawyers Guild.; National Maritime Union of America.; National Religion and Labor Foundation (U.S.); National Sharecroppers' Fund (U.S.).; Unión Nacional Sinarquista (Mexico); National Women's Trade Union League of America.; Oxford University Press.; Philosophical library.; Princeton University.; Progressive Party (U.S.: 1948); Reconstruction Finance Corporation.; Red International of Labor Unions.; Republican National Committee (U.S.); Revolutionary Workers League.; Russian Social-Democratic Labour Party.; Rutgers University.; Socialist Party of the United States of America.; Socialist Workers Party.; Southern Conference for Human Welfare.; Town Hall, Inc.; Trade Union Educational League (U.S.); Trade Union Unity League (U.S.); Transport Workers Union of America.; United States. Army.; United States Civil Service Commission.; United States. -- Congress. -- House.; United States. -- Congress. -- Senate.; United States. -- Department of Agriculture.; United States. -- Department of Justice.; United States. -- Department of State.; United States. -- Federal Security Agency.; United States Information Agency.; United States. -- Superintendent of Documents.; United States. -- National War Labor Board (1942-1945); United States. -- Office of War Information.; United States. -- Office of War Mobilization.; United States. -- Post Office Dept.; United States. -- Works Progress Administration.; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom.; Workers' Defense League.; Workers Library Publishers.; Workers Party of America.; World Jewish Congress.; Daily worker.; New masses.; Pravda (Moscow, Russia); Anti-Semitism.; Authors and publishers -- Soviet Union.; Authors and publishers -- United States.; Birobidzhan (Russia); Communism -- Algeria.; Communism -- Argentina.; Communism -- Australia.; Communism -- Austria.; Communism -- Bolivia.; Communism -- Brazil.; Communism -- Canada.; Communism -- Chile.; Communism -- China.; Communism -- Colombia.; Communism -- Costa Rica.; Communism -- Cuba.; Communism -- Czechoslovakia.; Communism -- France.; Communism -- Germany.; Communism -- Great Britain.; Communism -- Greece.; Communism -- Haiti.; Communism -- Honduras.; Communism -- Hungary.; Communism -- India.; Communism -- Ireland.; Communism -- Italy.; Communism -- Mexico.; Communism -- Morocco.; Communism -- New Zealand.; Communism -- Peru.; Communism -- Philippines.; Communism -- Poland.; Communism -- Puerto Rico.; Communism -- Spain.; Communism -- South Africa.; Communism -- Soviet Union.; Communism -- Uruguay.; Communism -- Venezuela.; Communism -- Yugoslavia.; Communism -- United States.; Labor movement.; Labor unions -- United States.; Politics and culture.; Publishers and publishing -- Soviet Union.; Publishers and publis
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Lists
  - Lists of Browder material (Box 1)
- Biographical material
  - Bio outlines and published biographies, undated (Box 1)
  - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 1)
  - Memorial service, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Personal documents (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - A, 1944-1947 (Box 2)
  - Abad Santos y Basco, José, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Abe, Yukio, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Abraham Lincoln School, Chicago, Illinois, 1943; 1944 (Box 2)
  - Academy of Science of the USSR, 1946 (Box 2)
  - L'Action Catholique, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Adams, C. B., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Adams, Josephine Truslow, 1945; 1946,; 1956,; 1959,; 1962,; undated (Box 2)
  - Aero Digest, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Agapov, Boris, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Agnoletti, Enzo Enriques, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Ainsley, Sheridan, 1946 (Box 2)
  - The Aircraft, 1936; worker-based union at Curtiss, Buffalo, NY (Box 2)
  - Albizu Campos, Pedro, 1936-1944 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Gross Wilbur, 1942; 1943 (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Robert J., 1950-1957 (Box 2)
  - All-America Anti-Imperialist League, 1929 (Box 2)
  - All Union Central Council of Trade Unions, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Allen, James, undated (Box 2)
  - Allen, Theodore William, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Alter, Victor, See Ehrlich Alter Case
  - Alvarez, G. Arnedo, See Communist Party, Argentina
  - Álvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Am-Rus Literary and Music Agency, 1954; 1955 (Box 2)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1951; undated (Box 2)
  - Amalgamated Plant Protection, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Amalgamated Public Service Workers' Union, undated (Box 2)
  - Amerasia, 1947 (Box 2)
  - America First Party, See Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth.
  - American Artist, 1947 (Box 2)
  - American Bar Association, 1945 (Box 2)
  - American Book Company, 1948 (Box 2)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1946 (Box 2)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1930-1952 (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Defense of Puerto Rican Political Prisoners, 1937 (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Liberation, 1958 (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1939-1944 (Box 2)
  - American Committee for the Resettlement of Jews in Birobidjan, 1937 (Box 2)
  - American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1943 (Box 2)
  - American Commonwealth Federation, 1935 (Box 2)
  - American Congress of Industry, 1942 (Box 2)
  - American Consular Service, Paris, 1921 (Box 2)
  - The American Economic Foundation, 1944 (Box 2)
  - American Exporter, 1947 (Box 2)
  - American Federation of Labor, 1933 (Box 2)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1939 (Box 2)
  - "American Forum of the Air," Mutual Broadcasting System, 1946; 1947 (Box 2)
  - American Fund for Public Service, 1929 (Box 2)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry, 1947; 1948 (Box 2)
  - American Labor Party, 1937-1953 (Box 3)
  - American Labor Party, Progressive Committee, 1940 (Box 3)
  - American League Against War and Fascism, 1933; 1934 (Box 3)
  - American Legion, 1943 (Box 3)
  - American Library Service, 1946 (Box 3)
  - The American Magazine, 1943 (Box 3)
  - American Negro Labor Congress, 1929 (Box 3)
  - American News Company, Inc, 1948 (Box 3)
  - American Overseas Airlines System, 1946 (Box 3)
  - American Retail Federation, 1944 (Box 3)
  - American Review of Soviet Medicine, 1947 (Box 3)
  - American Russian Institute, 1943; 1947 (Box 3)
  - American Scientist, 1947 (Box 3)
  - The American Scholar, 1947 (Box 3)